Sameeksha Nair . Jarvis Consulting

Hello! My name is Sameeksha Nair and I am a recent graduate from the University of Windsor where I did my Bachelor in Computer Science (Honours) with a specialization in Game Development. I am ambitious, passionate and super excited to start my journey into the tech industry to finally use the skills I have learnt these past 4 years. Through the course of my studies, I was able to expand my knowledge of tech and was even able to do 2 internships during my studies. I have ample experience working with game engines such as Unity and Unreal Engine, web development tools such as React and Node, databases such as MongoDB and SQL, data analytics tools such as Python and Tableau and even artificial intelligence primarily in Python. I have an interest in many different areas of tech and would love to learn more, explore and grow with the ever-changing market. I am eagerly looking forward to using the skills I have garnered to create software that could impact the world and make a difference.

Skills

Proficient: Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, Unity, React.js

Competent: Linux/Bash, Tableau, Selenium, Unreal Engine, Node.js, AWS, Eclipse

Familiar: Tensorflow, MongoDB, C#, PHP, Numpy/Pandas

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng SameekshaNair

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: An app that helps track the memory usage of the host system. Uses bash scripting for scripts, PostgreSQL and Docker for database and git for version control. Also, uses crontab to run script every minute.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- JDBC App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- Grep App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not Started
Spark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Login system using MERN stack [GitHub]: Implemented the classic login system in web apps using the MERN stack.

Fruit Collection Game with Inventory: Created in Unreal Engine. A simple fruit collection game (can be found on my website)

Evaluating different AI models: Evaluated the different regression models and neural networks using Google Colab and various Python libraries (numpy, pandas, sklearn, TensorFlow, etc)

Tic-Tac-Toe [GitHub]: Rendered the classic game of tic-tac-toe in C. Looking to create a GUI version.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis Consulting Group (December 2023-present): Developed projects using various technologies, which included implementing and testing. Attended daily scrum meetings with rest of the team to discuss work

Mobalytics Data Analytics Externship, Mobalytics (July 2023-September 2023): Researched the video gaming market to suggest new business prospects and ventures for the company. Cleaned and analyzed datasets collected using Microsoft Excel and Tableau. Collaborated with other externs to improve research articles and techniques. Delivered an impressive final presentation on the research and analysis done which gained praise from mentors and peers alike.

VR/AR Development Intern, CSKA Automation P Ltd (January 2022-May 2022): Aided in building an open world VR environment in Unreal Engine using C++ and blueprints. Created mini games, inventory system and other functionalities in the virtual world and delivered within the given deadlines. Supported building a dedicated server using the source version of Unreal Engine from the Epic Games GitHub. Used AWS cloud to host server and ensure its smooth running. Took part in the creative process such as world and UI design.

Education

University of Windsor (2019-2023), Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours), Computer Science - UWindsor: Deans Renewable Entrance Scholarship (2019-2023) - Dean's Honour Roll (2019, 2020)(2020, 2021)(2021, 2022)(2022, 2023) - LEAD Gold Medallion in recognition of efforts within and beyond the classroom in the areas of Leadership, Engagement, Application and Discovery in the Faculty of Science at the UWindsor - Grade: 87%

Miscellaneous

- Used to do dancing professionally with a crew
- Love singing and playing the guitar, always open to a fun karaoke night
- Love trying to learn new languages and discovering different kinds of cultures